Benjamin Smith Barton Papers 1789-1815 Mss.B.B284d
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Graphic materials, 1773-ca.1815; 2 boxes; 0.75 linear feet
  - Esculus parviflora [Also] Esculus flava [Also] Esculus pavia, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    "Esculus parviflora Also Esculus flava; Also Esculus pavia." Aesculus parviflora. Also A. flava; Also A. pavia [Elements, pl XV]. Plate. Shallus, sc. Class VII. Plate XIV. "Aesculus parviflora of Walter" = pl. XV Elements (1803).
  - Franklinia alatamaha, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
    Bart. Jou. Plate. Trenchard, sc.
  - Gentiana quinquefolia L., n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    "Tab. X[-] ined?"
  - Gopherus polyphemus, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    Turtle carapace. Trenchard, sc. See Bartram's Travels (Philadelphia, 1791).
  - Gopherus polyphemus, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    Turtle plastron. Trenchard, sc.
  - Great Alachua - Savana, East Florida, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing, 40.6 x 32.4 cm; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
    Other Finding Aids note
    Realms of Gold, 4 (1).
  - Ground Pine. Sarothra, Gentianoides and Rana, n.d.-1794; 1 watercolor; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
    Barton, Flora North America, iii, t. 92 [1823] not same.
  - Hamamelis virginica L., n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
  - Hedysarum violacium, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Also Diadelphia decandria and Robinia viscosa. Elements, pl. XXI.
  - Helenium from East Florida, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Identification in note pencilled by Bartram. (i.e. Coreopsis angustifolia Ait.)
  - Helianthus divaricatus, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    4 line legend on verso in Bartram's hand. Helianthus decapetalus L.? Elements, pl. XXIII.
  - Hibiscus (St. John's Rose), n.d.; 1 pen and ink sketch; Bartram, William
    [Torn sheet]. Perhaps Kosteletzkya virginica (L.) Presl.
  - Hymenocallis occidentalis LeConte, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    On verso: John Bartram, Jr.
  - Hypoxis erecta, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Also Lillium canadense.
  - Ipomoea sp., n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Resembles pl. 25 of Bartram's Botanical and Zoological Drawings (1968), but calyx very unlike. See also Elements, pl. II, fig. 3, which is reported to be "from Florida."
  - Larix laricina, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Also Apocynum sp. and Celastrus. Elements, pl. III, fig. 7.
  - Ludwigia alternifolia L., n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Elements, pl. X, fig. 2.
  - Magnolia acuminata Linn. [Cucumber tree], n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
  - Magnolia acuminata, 1803; 1 pen and ink sketch; Bartram, William
  - Magnolia auriculata, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
    Colored. Bart. Jour. Plate. Trenchard, sc.
  - Medeola virginica L., n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Elements, pl. XIV.
  - Mico-chlucco, King of the Muscogulges or Criks, call'd the Long Warrior, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Frontispiece for Travels (1791).
  - Napaea hermaphrodita. sp. plantar. Sida hermaphrodita (L.) Rusby, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Elements, pl. XX.
  - Nicotiana tabacum (Havana Tobacco), n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Used in Elements.
  - Oenothera grandiflora, 1 engraving; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
    Colored. Bart. Jour. Plate. Trenchard,sc.
  - Passiflora incarnata, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
  - Philadelphus inodorus, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Elements, pl. XVIII, in part.
  - Philadelphus inodorus, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    Plate. Cornelius Tiebout, sc. Elements, pl. XVIII, exactly.
  - Phlox, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Also includes Coreopsis (fig. 2).
  - Podophyllum peltatum, 1793; 1 engraving; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
    Engraving of roots, including Podophyllum peltatum, by Bartram. Tanner, engr. Elements, pl. II. Zephranthes atamasco (L.) Herb. Original drawing on which this engraving is based is filed under Barton, "roots" (lacking the Podophyllum).
  - Pyrola umbellata. Chimaphila umbellata (L.) Nutt, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Also Fig. 2: "Flower of Pyrola rotundifolia." Elements, pl. XXXIX (1836 ed., not in 1803 ed.). Chimaphila umbellata (L.) Nutt. Fig. 1 was used as a frontispiece in color in Priscilla Wakefield, Introduction to Botany.
  - Quercus pennsylvanicus heterophylla, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
  - Rhexia mariana L., n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Also includes Gaura biennis. Elements, pl. XVI part.
  - Rhododenron punctatum Andr., 1801; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
  - Robinia viscosa L., n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    Elements, pl. XXI.
  - Robinia viscosa L., n.d.; 1 proof; Bartram, William
    Elements, pl. XXI. Note on bottom indicates "Proof received June 4 1714[6?]"
  - Sagittaria sagittifolia, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    Includes pen and ink sketch of roots. Tanner Scr. Elements XXXV.
  - Sagittaria sagittifolia. Sagittaria engelmanniana. J.G. su., n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Elements pl. XXXVIII.
  - Salvia coccinea L., n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
  - Sarracenia purpurea L. [Pitcher plant], n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Elements, frontis.
  - Sarracenia purpurea L., n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
    Elements, frontis. Cornelius Tiebout, sc.
  - Silphium terebinthinum, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    Elements, pl. XXIV. Colored.
  - Silphium terebinthinum. Syng plog. necessaria, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Silphium terebinthaceum Jacq. Elements, pl. XXIV.
  - Subject unknown. [Botanical drawings], n.d.; 2 pen and ink drawings; Bartram, William
  - Testudo caelata, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William
    Verso contains Barton's 19-line description of the turtle.
  - Thaspium pinnatifidum (Buckl.) Gray?, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawings; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
  - Weasel, n.d.; 1 pen and ink drawing; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
  - Zanthorrhiza apiifolia, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    Colored. Lawson, sc. Elements, pl. XII.
  - Zanthorrhiza apiifolia, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William
    Uncolored proof. Lawson, sc. Elements, pl. XII.
  - Zanthorrhiza tinctoria, n.d.; 1 engraving; Bartram, William (Othertype OS)
    Colored. Elements, pl. XII.
  - Bat [reidentification: vespertilionid bat], n.d.; 1 watercolor
    Possibly the work of T. R. Peale.
  - Bats [reidentification: vespertilionid bat], n.d.; 1 pen and ink sketch (Othertype OS)
    Sketch of bat in flight, bat head.
  - Vesica Natatoria Trigl. Cucul. Lin. Bremae, 1807 September 12; 1 watercolor; Berkenkamp, Johann-Christoph
    Swim bladdder.
  - Saxifraga granulata, n.d.; 1 engraving; Capieux, Johann-Stephan
    Colored. Saxifraga sp.
  - Taraxacus officinale L., n.d.; 1 engraving; Capieux, Johann-Stephan
    Colored. Dandelion.
  - Chamaelirium luteum (L.) Gray, n.d.; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
  - Chicory family. One flower from composite head. = Echinops sp., n.d.; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
    "Undoubtedly used by B.S. Barton to illustrate his lectures."
  - Colutea arborescens, 1789 April 1; 1 engraving
    Colored print from Bot. Mag., t. 81
  - Conocephalus motif, n.d.; 1 watercolor
    Liverwort
  - Crapaud a pattes de Canard, n.d.; 1 item
    See Zak-rot.
  - Lacerta fasciata. Linn, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Denke, Christian Frederick,1775-1838.
    "Natural size & colors, common near Nazareth. A land kind, about old fences, old rotten trees, etc."
  - Dionaea muscipula, n.d.; 2 engravings
    Venus' fly-trap. Colored engravings. Adapted from John Ellis, cf. Elements, pl. VII. I. H. Seymour sc.
  - Elk skeleton and Human fetus, 2 engravings (Othertype OS)
  - Fucus asparagodes [No.] 7, n.d.; 1 item
    "These 'Fucus' 'sketches' are rather actual dried specimens of red algae, probably sent to Barton for identification (?) or collected by F. Pursh (?). Handwriting = Pursh (?)." J. Ewan, 9 August 1982.
  - Fucus conserva [No.] 11, n.d.; 1 item
  - Fucus conserva [No.] 12, n.d.; 1 item
  - Fucus conserva [No.] 10, n.d.; 1 item
  - Fucus conserva [No.] 6, n.d.; 1 item
  - Fucus conserva [s]tricta [P? or T?], n.d.; 1 item
  - Fucus fruticultory Wulf, n.d.; 1 item
  - Gladiolus communis, 1789; 1 engraving
    Colored print from Botanical magazine, t. 86
  - Hottentot girl, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Haines, William? (Othertype OS)
  - Cynocephalus pabio, n.d.; 1 engraving; Hamilton (Othertype OS)
    J.E. Ridinger, sc. Baboon.
  - Hibiscus syriacus L., 1789; 1 engraving
    Colored print from Botanical mag., t. 83.
  - Homology - Arms and legs, 1 engraving
    APS owns the copperplate
  - Megalonyx jeffersoni claw, n.d.; 1 item; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868
  - Megalonyx jeffersoni ungual, n.d.; 1 item; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868
  - Megalonyx jeffersoni unguals and claw, 3 pencil and ink sketches; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868
  - Tooth fossil [reidentification: ground sloth claw?], 1 watercolor; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868
  - Tooth fossil [reidentification: lateral view of ground sloth claw], 1 watercolor; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868
  - Tooth fossil [reidentification: sketch for APSimg6264, ground sloth claw?], 1 pen and ink sketch; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868 (Othertype OS)
  - Tooth fossil [reidentification: sketch for APSimg6265, lateral view of ground sloth claw], 1 pen and ink sketch; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868 (Othertype OS)
  - Tooth fossil [reidentification: proximal articulation of ground sloth claw], 1 watercolor; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868 (Othertype OS)
  - Two arrow heads, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868 (Othertype OS)
  - Cornus florida L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868
    Stems and buds.
  - Horned lizard, n.d.; 1 engraving
    Two views: lateral and ventral, with view of head from front. Original plate at the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. Initial drawing possibly done by Charles Willson Peale. A. Lawson, Engraver
  - Hyoscyamus aureus, 1789; 1 engraving
    Colored print from botanical magazine, pl. 87.
  - Iasione capensis, n.d.; 1 engraving
    Jasione capensis. Akrel, sc. Pl. X
  - Jeffersonia diphylla, n.d.; 1 engraving (Othertype OS)
    Named in honor of Thomas Jefferson by B.S. Barton. Cf. APS. Transactions, v. 3.
  - Kalmia floridana, 1773; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
    Foliis Galabris, Lanceolatis, Carolla Campulae Hypocraterique Forma. Copy from Bernard Romans, 1773.
  - Kalmia latifolia L., 1773; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
    Copy of a copy of Bernard Romans, 1773.
  - Adoxa moschatellina L., n.d.; 1 engraving; Kilburn, Lawrence
  - Mastodon skull, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Krandman, O. (Othertype OS)
  - Rattlesnake anatomy, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Othertype XOS)
    These rattlesnake drawings were originally attributed to B.S. Barton
  - Rattlesnake internal organs, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Rattlesnake muscles of the Scuta, taken from the 75th rib towards the tail, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    [Also] Rattlesnake "muscles of the back and side. Squamal muscles." These drawings were originally attributed to B.S. Barton.
  - Rattlesnake organs of generation, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Rattlesnake stomach, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Rattlesnake tail, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Rattlesnake, anatomy of the tail, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    These drawings were originally attributed to B.S. Barton.
  - Salamander, 1 pen and ink drawing; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    These drawings were originally attributed to B.S. Barton, but reattributed by Latrobe Papers.
  - Lepidoptera. Order Lepidoptera. Genus Sphinx, n.d.; 1 engraving
    Plate VIII. Entomology. G. Murray, sc.
  - Lepidoptera, n.d.; 1 watercolor
    Moths
  - Lepidoptera, n.d.; 1 watercolor
  - Lepidoptera, n.d.; 1 pencil sketch
  - Lepiota procera, n.d.; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
  - Limnanthemum aquaticum (Walt.). Larger floating heart., n.d.; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
    Larger floating heart.
  - Lion Marin. Zee-Leeuw (Sea lion), n.d.; 1 engraving
    Plate. J.V. Schley, direx.
  - Lionne Marine. Zee-Leeuwin (Sea lion), n.d.; 1 engraving
  - Lophilia americana (Pursh) Cou., n.d.; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
  - Melilotus supina latifolia siliqua lata membranacea compressa, n.d.; 1 engraving
    Print from Commelin, Soc. Reg. Sc. Tom. I, tab. XIII, p.213.
  - Map of the Seat of War among the Creek Indians, 1814; 1 map; Melish, John (Othertype XOS)
    Extra-Oversized, see Call No. 660/1814/M485ci.
  - Alligator, 1810; 1 pen and ink sketch; Nunes, Abraham I. (Othertype OS)
  - Coreopsis, n.d.; 1 engraving; Nunes, Abraham I.
    Francis Kearny sc.
  - Quercus sp., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Nunes, Abraham I. (Othertype OS)
  - Wasp Nest, 1792; 1 watercolor; Palisot de Beauvois, Ambrose-Marie-François-Joseph, 1752-1820
    "The hive of the Wasp call'd Vespa maculata, from pensilvania near Philadelphia. Drawn, and presented to me, by my friend, Mr. P. de Beauvois, 1792. B.S. Barton."
  - Allium canadense L.?, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Anemone canadensis L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Asclepias quadrifolia Jacq., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Calochortus elegans Pursh, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820
  - Campanula divaricata Michx, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820
  - Clitoria mariana L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Crinum americanum L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Cucullaria rosea. Dicentra eximia (Ker.) Torr., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820
    Also includes Dicentra eximia flower and calyx.
  - Dicentra (cultivar?), n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Digitalis purpurea L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Epipactis unifolia. Calypso bulbosa (L.) Oakes, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820
    Also includes Calypso bulbosa.
  - Fritillaria lanceolata Pursh, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
    Fig. 1. Also Fritillaria pudica.
  - Habenaria orbiculata Pursh Torr., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Hydrastis canadensis L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Iris Fulva [Red Brown Flag], n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Iris fulva Ker., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
    Synonym: I. Cuprea Pursh.
  - Iris prismatica Pursh?, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Kalmia latifolia L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820
    Note on previous folder suggested that this illustration was probably too "delicate" to be done by Pursh but not delicate enough to be done by Turpin.
  - Lilium catesbaei L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Peramium pubescens (Willd.) MacM., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Purshia tridentata (Pursh), n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820
  - Pycanthemum flexuosum Walt., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
    Synonym: Pycanthemum linifolium Pursh.
  - Pycanthemum linifolium Pursh. [See Pycanthemum flexuosum (Walt.)]., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820
  - Ribes aureum Pursh, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Ribes (Glossularia) rotundifolium Michx., 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Sabbatia angularis (L.) Pursh., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Sagittaria acutifolia, 1800; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820
  - Sclerolepsis uniflora Walt., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Steironema lanceolatum Walt., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820 (Othertype OS)
  - Quercus plaustris [Pin oak], n.d.; 1 engraving; Redoute, Pierre Joseph
    Plate from the French edition of F.A. Michaux's North American Oaks, and in F.A. Michaux's North American Sylva (Philadelphia: Wm. Rutter & Co., 1865), v.1, pl. 27.
  - Sarracenia flava L. flower., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Redoute, Pierre Joseph (Othertype OS)
  - Sarracenia flava L. leaf., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Redoute, Pierre Joseph (Othertype OS)
  - The Bear, 1748; 1 engraving; Ridinger, J. E. (Othertype OS)
  - Sailing ship, 23 Feb. 181[5?]; 1 pen and ink drawing
    "Perhaps a view of the ship Barton took to Europe, 1815." Feb. 23, 181[5?]
  - Sarothra gentianoides, n.d.; 1 watercolor
  - Sarracenia sp., [Leaf], n.d.; 1 watercolor
    Possibly done by Turpin.
  - Plantes. Gewassen. German edition Dampier. Plate., 1 engraving; Schley, J. V (Othertype OS)
  - Semen Badian, seu, Anisum stellatum ant Illicium Floridanum De copia Originali Bernardi Romans, del. 1773, 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
  - Silene virginica, n.d.; 1 engraving (Othertype OS)
    Francis Kearny, sc.
  - Silene virginica, n.d.; 1 proof
    Tissue proof. Francis Kearny, sc.
  - Silene virginica, n.d.; 1 watercolor (Othertype OS)
  - Silhouette of a Hottentot girl, 1802 June; 1 silhouette
    Drawn at the Cape of Good Hope, June 1802. Probably by William Haines.
  - Silhouette of a man, n.d.; 1 silhouette
    "Cut with Scissors by Master Hobard without Drawing or Machine."
  - Nepenthes, n.d.; 1 engraving; Smith, James Edward
    IX, 236.
  - Spartium junceum, 1789; 1 engraving
    Colored print from botanical magazine, t. 85.
  - Bufo cornutus brasiliensis, 1804 February 3; 1 engraving; Tilesius von Tilenau, Wilhelm Gottfried
    Colored. "Arantango Bras. Itanga Lusilanis. Tilesius ad vie pinxit Brasiliae." Horned toad.
  - Sea anemone, n.d.; 1 colored engraving; Tilesius von Tilenau, Wilhelm Gottfried (Othertype OS)
    T.I, Tab. XIV.
  - Sea anemone, n.d.; 1 colored engraving; Tilesius von Tilenau, Wilhelm Gottfried (Othertype OS)
    Plate XV, Vol. I Memories de L'Acad. Imp. Des Sciences
  - Tulip, n.d.; 1 engraving
    Colored. Tulipa sp. Pl. 25
  - Acer rubrum, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Alnus rugosa (Du Roi) K. Koch, n.d.; 1 item; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
  - Amsonia. Amsonia salicifolia Pursh, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Amsonia. Amsonia tabernaemontana Walt., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Andromeda calyculata, 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Andromeda racemosa, 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Annona triloba, n.d.; 1 engraving; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Aquilegia canadensis, n.d.; 1 colored engraving; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Asarum canadense L., n.d.; 1 pencil sketch; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Asclepias incarnata L., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Bartonia verna, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Bartonia verna, n.d.; 1 pen and ink sketch. 1 engraving; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
  - Bartramia pomiformis, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
  - Betula populifolia L., n.d.; 2 engravings; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
    Elements, pl. XXXVI]. Francis Kearny, sc. (2 plates).
  - "Betula Serrulata Ait." Alnus Regosa (Du Roi) K. Koch, n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Caulophyllum thalictroides (L.) Michx. [See Leontice thalictroides]., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - "Comptonia asplendifolia." Comptonia Peregrina, 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - "Corylus Cornuta." Corylus rostrata (Ait.)., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Corylus rostrata (Ait.)., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Dentaria Laciniata Muhl, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
  - Dracontium [Skunk cabbage]., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Erythronium americanum, n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Dogtooth violet.
  - "Fumaria Cucullaria." Dicentra cucullaria (L.) Torr., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Halesia tetraptera L., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Silver bell tree.
  - Helonias bullata L., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Jeffersonia diphylla L., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Named in honor of Thomas Jefferson by B.S. Barton. See A.P.S. Transactions, v. 3 (1793): 312.
  - "Laurus Aestivalis." Lindera benzoin (L.) Blume., 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - "Laurus Benzoin." Lindera benzoin (L.) Blume., 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - "Leontice thalictroides." Caulophyllum thalictroides (L.) Michx., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Lilium grayi wats, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Or, Lilium canadense L. atypical? = Lilium canadense var. editorum Fern.
  - Lithospermum gmelini (Michx.), n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    A.S. Hitchc.
  - Magnolia acuminata. Plate. B. Tanner, sc., n.d.; 1 engraving, 2 copies; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Intended for DECADES.
  - Magnolia acuminata., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Morphological figures, n.d.; 1 engraving; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
    "Tom. 7, Pl. II" Plee, sc.
  - Myrica gale L.?, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Pixydanthera barbulata Michx., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Pogonia verticillata (Willd.) Nutt., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Polytrichum commune, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
  - Prunus maritima Wang., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Pteridosperm, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Fossil fern pinnule
  - Pteridosperm, n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François
    Fossil fern pinnule. Possibly by J. H. Hopkins?
  - Rhus aromaticum Michaux and Rhus suaveolens Aiton, 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Rhus Aroma - Tica Ait.
  - Ribes cereum Pursh., n.d.; 1 watercolor; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
    Differs from other sketch in details of flower dissection but surely same sp. Though corolla lobes rounded here, acute in other sketch.
  - Sambucus pubescentia Mich., n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)
  - Saxifraga nivalis, n.d.; 1 watercolor and ink drawing; Turpin, Pierre Jean François (Othertype OS)